[Music]
welcome my name is baj Kota I'm a PM
working for Microsoft and today we will
talk about improvements in user
experience in business Central 2024 Wave
2 we have some exciting new changes for
you to see so let's get started and
we'll talk about access Keys first this
feat Fe allows you to access actions and
features of business Central using
keyboard shortcuts this feature was
available or is already available in
business Central uh since 2023 but only
in English and with this wave we are
bringing this feature to additional
languages the feature is available when
you press ALT key a small keytips show
up on screen uh indicating which key
comp comination you have to press in
order to reach to that
feature and then when we are developing
this feature for additional languages we
are trying to be consistent we are
trying to keep some special uh key
combin combinations and system actions
uh using the same uh the same Keys the
same key strokes you can read more about
that at the following link but also
please remember that access Keys is not
the only feature available for you to be
productive in business Central because
we also have other keyboard shortcuts
system keyboard shortcuts various
application keyboard shortcuts and so on
and so forth so please have a look at
our documentation talking about using
business Central with keyboard we have
interesting changes related to search
and that is search in data search and
lists uh and search even in the filter
pane in this wave we introduce multiple
changes behind the scenes you will have
other sessions in this event talking
about uh server changes related to a
search
optimization uh but essentially we
introducing a search that is based on a
full text search
technology rather than marching
characters this allows for the search to
be much faster and more flexible for the
users let's see that in a demo when I in
business Central and I go to a list
which is enabled for that modernized
search let's go to items I can see in my
search box right now two different
options the modern search and the Legacy
search if I would choose the Legacy
search and try London
chair that item is not found because
there is no exact match this Legacy
search was based on specific matching of
the search term or
characters when I switched to the modern
search this item was found because we
were able to match individual words not
only that this search experience is much
faster and because it is based on a
special full text index based on columns
that are indicated with this little
icon as a developer you can also control
which columns
are optimized for this new search
experience and you can also extend
business Central H and add that specific
parameter to um to our tables I
encourage you to tune in to other
recordings in this collection where my
colleagues are talking about this
technology from the developers
perspective this feature is coming in
waves uh it will be delivered starting
from October and it will show up for
multiple tables in business Central
starting from the main data like items
and customers and sales orders and then
uh being available also for other tables
later on during this
wave let's talk about additional
features and we'll talk about resizing
column first we have this feature in the
product already but it was always based
on personalization and personalization
is not always enabled you can disable
personalization for a given role and
also there are some pages in The Product
Where personalization is not possible
and then uh resizing columns uh was not
enabled in this wave you will see that
the experience to resize columns is much
faster it is stored locally in your
browser but it is still based on
personalization when needed uh that way
it is um available for pages that were
not U enabled before like for instance
co-pilot prompt dialogue Pages where you
have results from your co-pilot and now
you can resize columns and and
manipulate that much easier and then of
course if your personalization is
enabled your choices will be stored
within your profile as before
we have also added a new parameter to
the web client where you can control the
layout of the page and that way you can
force the business Central web client to
open is in specific layout and most
notably you can open in analysis mode so
you can create links and share analysis
mode um between users and that way open
the analysis mod directly directly using
uh a single link and of course that also
supports other modes so you can open a
standard list a tiles or or even tall
tiles this feature is coming in 25.1 so
you will expect that uh release a little
bit uh later than than just uh at the
beginning of October all right let's
talk about attachments and uploading
files over to you
Ian so thank you BL so drag and drop uh
functionality to attach multiple files
in business Central uh makes it easier
to manage files or even folders as you
will see this feature benefits users who
work with multiple files and adds value
to organizations by enhancing data
organization accessibility while making
users uh more productive so what better
way to to see that but to see it in
action so let's switch to the demo let
me start by showing you the first place
where you can actually manage multiple
files all of you are well aware of a
purchase order and the purchase
documents usually have some incoming
files Associated to them right now being
a uh purchasing agent I can see I
received a invoice and my company also
requires me to provide some additional
sort of proof of work before U re
receiving uh services or sending that
purchase order uh for for further
invoicing what I can do today and this
is a new action that we've added you can
add uh supporting documents and an
interesting thing uh you can see right
now it says drop files means it can
handle now multiple files so I can pick
like two or three files and simply drag
them uh in here they got uploaded and
you can see that in the list what's even
more cool about this thing is you can
actually today you can actually drop a
whole folder uh in an upload uh in in a
new upload files dialog so this is one
place where you can actually handle
where users can handle uh multiple file
uploads another thing where the most of
our users are using this is also
document attachments as you can see on
top in here we have this Legacy
attachment uh fact box and this is a new
uh attachments U fact box that can now
handle uh multiple files you have the
well-known and the same actions that
existed in the uh Legacy attachments so
you can simply click upload files again
uh drag or drop or select multiple files
in there and you can actually execute
the the well-known actions like opening
the file in one drive or actually
looking at the list of the attached
documents as you were uh you were used
to doing that before and the third place
where you can actually um see all of
that is in the email uh send email
dialogue so I'll go to the vendor and
I'll set send email and now if you
scroll down and if you want to add uh
multiple attachments again you can
simply uh drag or drop uh multiple files
or you can select them manually and
that's it so what you saw in this demo
was a new document attachments uh
component and as you saw it can be
accessed from multiple places from
incoming documents from document
attachments from email dialogue these
are basically the places where more than
90% of uh business Central users
actually uses uh to upload uh files the
files can now be uploaded either one by
one or you can select multiple or you
can even pick uh the folders you get a
quick and easy overview of the files and
of course um you you can do all of that
with the way uh way last clicks and
don't forget uh one other thing that
Legacy document attachments part of the
factbox is now getting obsoleted so it's
perfectly fine to go to a
personalization settings and once your
users get used to the the new document
attachments you can hide uh the old
one and that's that's not all of course
uh handling multiple file uploads comes
also with a support uh for uh Al
developers you now have two new
properties on action that you can Define
that an action is going to handle
multiple file uploads you can Define
allowed file extensions and there is a
also a trigger that can handle the
upload of U upload of those files that
users have selected if you want to learn
more about that make sure to check out
uh 2024 release way 1 uh video on what's
new in uh developer tools these
properties were explained already uh in
there and that's it all right thank you
Ian that was great and this is all in
this recording thank you very much